Krista Lowry, Data Analyst

Seattle, WA | 315-690-0039 | kristahlowry@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven self-starter with 10 years experience building and optimizing digital products and marketing strategies using the power of data analysis and experimentation. Strong communication skills across technical and non-technical teams including senior leadership. Committed to leading efficient and impactful teams.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- A/B and multivariate testing
- SQL proficiency
- Agile methodology
- Cross-functional collaboration
- Project management

- Data visualization & reporting (Tableau, Power Bl, Looker)
- User research & behavior tracking
- Requirements documentation
- Tag Management

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Senior Optimization Analyst, Aug 2021 to present, System1, Bellevue WA

Company description: Customer acquisition technology and media platform.

Responsible for driving experimentation across 4 business flows, performing high-visibility data analysis for key business initiatives, and partnering closely with engineering and design teams to build and test new features.

- Designed and executed 150+ A/B and multivariate tests, ensuring statistically significant results through systematic sample size and test parameter selection.
- Built 20+ Tableau dashboards to surface ad-hoc and operational data analysis for marketing teams and senior leadership
- Scoped out new business opportunities through strategic A/B testing, partnering with cross-functional teams
- Conducted **cohort and funnel analysis** by wrangling 1M+ rows of internal user behavior and demographic data using SQL and R. Identified an experiment opportunity in a specific geo market that yielded 12% revenue lift.
- Tested **ad placements and yield management strategies**, collaborating closely with the display advertising team.
- Ensured **compliance** laws (GDPR/CCPA) and best practices were upheld in both **paid and organic** search engine flows.
- Managed intake of stakeholder experiment requests, **RICE scoring**, and facilitated communication on **experiment designs and timelines**.
- Managed projects relating to winning experiment rollouts and both primary and secondary CRO metric collection
- Spearheaded **Agile methodology** adoption. Increased rate of iteration & ideation cycle by 2x.
- Led biweekly meetings with stakeholders to present findings, rollout plans, iteration proposals.
- Led sprint planning and retros for a 6 person team.
- Mentored junior team members

Marketing Data & BI Analyst, Feb 2017 to Aug 2021 - Scotsman Guide, Bothell WA Company description: B2B Fintech and media platform for mortgage industry professionals Served as analytics and optimization lead on the team that built and launched a new subsidiary company, while also leading analytics for the parent company. Focused on building out the web analytics reporting stack, supporting UX design decisions with user behavior data and research, and improving data literacy across the organization.

- Conducted **UX research and user testing** using SurveyMonkey, UserTesting.com and CrazyEgg to determine information architecture and landing page design.
- Conducted A/B tests using Google Optimize to increase lead generation and website conversions.
- Wrote user stories and participated in a scrum team as a part of Agile methodologies.
- Established KPIs and created **Power BI dashboards** to monitor client success and identify top/bottom performing clients.
- Led monthly web analytics review and strategy meetings with company leadership.
- Managed contract workers and interns

Digital Marketing Coordinator, Dec 2014 to Feb 2017 - *Scotsman Guide, Bothell WA Company description: B2B Fintech and media platform for mortgage industry professionals* **Promoted to position** after 1.5 years as editorial/production assistant. Assumed ownership of web analytics and online content management. Was part of the core team that launched a major website redesign, serving as the **analytics and CMS lead**, working closely with engineering.

- Built dashboards and **published company-wide weekly reports** on web analytics performance.
- Wrote **user requirements documentation** for the website redesign, including user stories and tracking requirements
- Revamped and managed digital marketing initiatives including Google AdWords and SEO
- Implemented and managed **Google Tag Manager**: defined measurement plans, wrote tracking tags, coordinated with engineering to set up data layer, set guidelines for code management
- Managed CMS: maintained infrastructure, URL redirects, SEO metadata, trained internal users

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Marketing Analytics: Google Analytics 4, Google Tag Manager, Optimize, Hotjar, Google Ad Manager, VWO, Optimizely, User Testing, Survey Monkey
- Project Management: Slack, Jira, Confluence, Trello, Smartsheet, LucidChart
- Data Visualization: Tableau, Power BI, Looker Studio
- Software, Databases & Languages: GitHub, Visual Studio Code, SQL, R, Python, DAX, Regex, Javascript, Wordpress CMS, Snowflake

EDUCATION

Certificate of Data Analytics: Techniques for Decision Making, 2023, UW

- Studied **exploratory data analysis** techniques using **RStudio** and **SQL**. Conducted predictive analysis using **machine learning models** such as linear and logistic regression, KNN clustering.
- Psychology Architectures of Digital Behavior Change, 2016, Behavioral Design Academy
 - Studied behavioral change theories and **psychological design patterns** as they relate to digital experiences. Translated these principles into **wireframes** and **user journey maps**

Certificate in Digital Marketing Analytics, 2015, University of Washington

• Studied digital marketing strategies and techniques across channels such as paid acquisition, SEO, display, affiliate and social media marketing. Built marketing plans to measure ROI.

Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy, Graduated in 2012, cum laude. GPA: 3.58 SUNY Purchase College

• Specialized in phenomenology and existentialism philosophies